

# **ARCHIT BHARDWAJ**

## **Software Developer**

### Lancaster, UK | architbhardwaj88@gmail.com

Senior software engineer with 9+ years of experience in the full software development cycle, specializing in C#, SQL, and JS frameworks like React. Constantly honing my skillset to stay up-to-date with the latest technologies. Recently I have developed proficiency in DevOps, especially in the use of Infrastructure as Code (IAC) tools such as Terraform for Azure and automation of Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery (CI/CD). Additionally, I am comfortable working both independently and collaboratively, with previous experience in mentoring.

# **SKILLS**

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

- Strong knowledge of server-side technologies: C#, Python, Node.js, GraphQL.
- Proficient in front-end technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript frameworks like React and Vue.js.

# CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS (CMS):

Experience working with CMS technologies like Contentful.

#### **DATABASE TECHNOLOGIES:**

- Experience with relational databases: SQL, PostgreSQL.
- Familiarity with NoSQL databases: MongoDB, Cassandra.

#### **DEVOPS:**

- Proficient in working with cloud platforms: AWS, Azure, GCP.
- Experience with DevOps practices, including continuous integration, deployment, and testing
- Proficient in managing/creating infrastructure using IAC(Terraform).
- Familiarity with containerization technologies: Docker and Kubernetes.

#### SERVERLESS AND CLOUD COMPUTING:

- Proficient in serverless architectures and technologies.
- Experience with serverless platforms like AWS Lambda, Azure Functions, or Google Cloud Functions.
- Experience in managing and deploying services on Azure app service, AWS EC2
- Understanding of event-driven and microservices architectures.

#### SYSTEM ARCHITECTURE AND DESIGN:

- Knowledge of microservices architecture and API design.
- Ability to design, implement, and maintain scalable, high-performance systems.

#### WEB APPLICATION SECURITY:

- Knowledge of security best practices.
- Experience implementing security measures in web applications.

#### **TEAMWORK AND LEADERSHIP:**

- Ability to work with and have lead cross-functional teams, including developers, designers, and product managers.
- Excellent collaboration and communication skills.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **CODE COMPUTER LOVE**

## Senior Software Engineer | Feb 2022 - Current

- .NET Core(C#) and SQL, Azure, AWS
- REST API and GraphQL
- React and NextJS for front end development
- Implemented automated Deployment and CI on AWS, Azure using IAC
- Worked individually and as a team using agile methodologies where appropriate.
- Interacting with clients and their developers for the purpose of integrating systems.
- Database architecture and solution design.
- Mentor Junior developers

#### **OPEN ECX**

Senior Software Developer | Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

- Work on a high traffic system based on ASP.NET(C#), Blazor and SQL
- Maintained and created services on Azure app services using
- Handled Dev support for all clients which enhanced my working under pressure skills
- Refactored system to adhere to OOP concepts
- DevOps: Build and Release cycles
- Dealing with Clients/ Client developers in relation to integrations.
- Database architecture / solution design

### **ACCESSPLANIT**

Software Developer | Jan 2014 - Sept 2021

- Lead a team of 8 developers towards the last couple of years
- Work on a high traffic system based on ASP.NET(C#) and SQL, React, Azure
- Implemented automated Deployment and CI
- Handled Dev support for all clients which enhanced my working under pressure skills
- Refactored system to adhere to OOP concepts
- Focused on TDD.
- DevOps: Build and Release cycles
- Dealing with Clients/ Client developers in relation to integrations.
- Database architecture / solution design

# **EDUCATION**

### LANCASTER UNIVERSITY

1st class (Hons) BEng Computer Science | Jun 2007 - Jun 2010